Curriculum Vitae

Introduction

I am an energetic and hardworking person with high attention to detail. I have developed strong communication skills enabling me to communicate with a wide range of people.

I marry my former experience in Industrial Design with the Hospitality Sector through productiveness from my understanding on delivering to consumers either products or services with high standards.

EDUCATION

2021.2019 Diploma in International Hospitality Management

Griffith College, Limerick, Ireland

2013.2008 Bachelor's Degree in Industrial Design Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana, Unidad Xochimilco, Mexico City

> 2008.2004 Computing Technician Dr. John J. Sparks, Coatza. Ver. México

2007.2006 Rotary Exchange Student Seminaire du Floreffe, Belgium

TRAINING

2013-2018 Packaging Engeenering Certification

IMPEE

2013 Entrepreneurship of Cultural Business

UAM-X

2012 Product Photography, ENAF 2011 Studio Photography, ENAF

LANGUAGES

Spanish / Native English / Fluent

[TOEFL +550, 2016] [IELTS 6.5,2018]

French / Fluent

[DELF B1 certification]

Portuguese / Intermediate

SOFTWARE SKILLS PERSONAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office Teamwork player

Autocad Time Management

Rhinoceros + VRay Quick Learner

SolidWorks + Photoview Effective Communication 3D Studio Max + Vray Problem Solvina

Keyshot Sense of Responsability

Illustrator Proactivite

Photoshop Strategic Creative

MaxCut Sense of Urge

Work Experience

2017 to Present

Supervisor, Zumo, Ireland Staff training

Time Management Daily stock preparation

POS operation

Sales and Customer service

Drink preparation

Daily based cleaning

Stock levels reports

Health and Safety procedures

Cleaning maintenance equipment: Industrial Citrus Juicer and Nutrifaster N450

Social Media Content Design and Management

2016-2017

Industrial Designer, Marketing Creative, Helio Group, Mexico

Brands: Mattel (Cars, Fisher Price, Barbie, Justice League, Mega Construx, Boomco, Hot Wheels), José Cuervo (José Cuervo, Reserva de la familia, Bushmills, Macallan,

etc), Nestle, Garnier, Manura

Brief interpretation

Concept development

Sketching, 3D Modelling and Rendering

Materials and finishing proposal

Site measurement

Production planes

2015-2016

Industrial Designer, Project Manager, Sinnarg, Mexico

Brand: Cartier Watch & Cartier Lunette

Interpretation of planes and tropicalization for production

Parametric 3D Modelling

Planes for production development, reengineering, cut lists and finishing specifications

CAD files development for CAM production

Suppliers' and manufacturers selection and accreditation based on brand requirements

Purchasing orders request

Materials' approval reception

Stock management

Production management

Finishing sampling register and storage according to customer's approvals

Finishing quality supervision

Exportation packaging engineering

Budget management

Installation and maintenance organisation and administration

Installation and maintenance supervisor

2012-2013

Volunteering: Laboratory assistant for research of ceramic materials at DIX's Ceramics Laboratory, UAM, Mexico

Design and development of utilitarian objects

Clay and glassing weighing and preparation

Sampling material modelling and glassing

Stock storage and organisation

Gypsum lathing and moulding development

Paste deflocculating and casting

High and medium temperature kiln supervision

Finishing application: over glaze, under glaze, marble effect, crazing hair crack,

burnish, polish, and patina

Design assistant for traditional pottery at Pottery Studies Center in San Miguel

Tenextatiloyan, Puebla, Mexico

CONTACT DETAILS:









Sexton St, Limerick, Ireland